Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we have an intermediate level lesson for you.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节中级课程。
It's kind of about cars, right?
这跟车有点关系，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So today we are taking our car to the mechanic and we're just going to check things and make
所以今天我们要把车开到修车厂，
sure that our car is okay.
检查一下确保车况良好。
All right.
好的。
So we're going to learn a lot of really great words that have to do with cars and what happens
我们会学到很多跟汽车相关的实用词汇，
when cars break down.
以及汽车出故障时的情况。
So let's listen to our dialogue.
那我们来听一下对话吧。
Welcome to Al's Garage.
欢迎来到Al's修车厂。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
No problem at all.
完全没问题。
I am taking a long road trip and I want to make sure my car is in good mechanical condition.
我要开长途旅行，想确保车况良好。
Very wise decision.
非常明智的决定。
When was the last time you had a tune-up?
你上次做保养是什么时候？
Not that long ago.
没多久之前。
I think it was four months ago.
我想是四个月前。
We usually recommend that you bring your car in every 5,000 kilometers.
我们通常建议每5000公里来检查一次。
Why?
为什么？
I mean, what exactly do you do to a car that you need to check it so often?
我是说，到底要对车做什么检查，需要这么频繁？
First of all, we change the motor oil and oil filter.
首先，我们会更换机油和机油滤清器。
If you don't do this, it can cause your engine to wear faster and that means you would probably
如果不这样做，会导致发动机磨损加快，
have to change the pistons and intake valves.
那就可能得换活塞和进气阀了。
I see.
我明白了。
What else?
还有什么？
We also check your spark plugs, fuel filter, and other oil levels such as hydraulic fluid.
我们还会检查火花塞、燃油滤清器，以及其他油液，比如液压油。
We also check the clutch and brakes to determine when you will need new ones.
还会检查离合器和刹车，判断什么时候需要更换。
Okay.
好的。
Well, when you put it that way, it doesn't seem like a waste of time and money.
嗯，听你这么一说，这倒不像是浪费时间和钱了。
Trust me.
相信我。
Regular tune-ups will keep your car running smoothly and avoid breakdowns.
定期保养能让你的车运行顺畅，避免抛锚。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So a very simple dialogue with the mechanic explaining to the client about why you need
这段对话很简单，修车师傅向客户解释了
to take care of your car.
为什么需要保养车。
So he mentioned a couple of very technical words in here.
他提到了几个很专业的词。
Let's take a look at those on Language Takeaway.
我们来看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
The first phrase we're looking at today is tune-up.
今天要学的第一个短语是tune-up。
So a tune-up is a thing, it's a noun, and it's something you do to check your car.
Tune-up是个名词，指的是对车进行检查。
Right.
对。
So you take your car for a tune-up or you get a tune-up.
所以你可以说“把车送去保养”或“做一次保养”。
Now this is for your car and this basically means to check that your car is okay and replace
这是针对车的，基本上就是检查车况，
any very easy things around the car.
并更换一些简单的部件。
So you don't normally get a tune-up when your car is broken.
通常车坏了不会去做保养。
You get a tune-up when your car is okay.
车况好的时候才做保养。
That's right.
没错。
So the mechanic explained some of the things that you do when you get a tune-up.
修车师傅解释了保养时做的一些事情。
So for example, he said that they change the motor oil.
比如，他说他们会更换机油。
Okay, so like it sounds, motor oil is oil for your motor.
对，顾名思义，机油就是发动机用的油。
That's right.
没错。
And there are other kinds of oil as well and oil is oftentimes put into the car and then
还有其他种类的油，油经常被加进车里，
sometimes it falls out.
有时也会漏出来。
And so what's that thing that catches the oil when it comes down?
那油漏下来时接住它的东西叫什么？
It's called an oil pan.
叫油底壳。
So yes, as you said, there are different types of oils.
是的，就像你说的，有不同类型的油。
Cooking oil is obviously for cooking, for eating.
食用油当然是用来做饭、吃的。
But motor oil is not for eating, it's for your motor.
但机油不是用来吃的，是给发动机用的。
But we also have to change the oil filter.
我们还得更换机油滤清器。
Now this is an important part that often gets mentioned at tune-ups.
这是保养时经常提到的重要部件。
That's right.
没错。
So the word filter here, you have the verb to filter.
Filter这个词，有动词形式“过滤”。
In this case, we also have a noun, it's called a filter.
这里它是名词，叫滤清器。
So what this device does, it collects maybe dirt or rocks and dust or anything that you
这个装置的作用是收集灰尘、石子、污垢等
don't want to be in your engine and specifically maybe if the oil is a little bit dirty.
你不希望进入发动机的东西，特别是如果机油有点脏的话。
Right, so an oil filter makes sure that the oil in your motor is not going to harm your
对，机油滤清器确保发动机里的机油不会损害发动机。
motor.
And we also have a couple of interesting things like the fuel filter.
我们还有一些有趣的东西，比如燃油滤清器。
Now how is this different from the oil filter?
它和机油滤清器有什么不同？
It's pretty much the same thing.
基本一样。
The only difference is that this filter specifically cleans the gasoline in your car.
唯一的区别是这个滤清器专门清洁车里的汽油。
Okay, similar object.
好的，类似的东西。
After that, we have something very different.
之后，我们有一个很不同的东西。
These are spark plugs.
这是火花塞。
That's right.
没错。
These are small little devices that, as the name says, create a spark.
这些小装置，顾名思义，会产生火花。
This is how your engine goes.
发动机就是这样工作的。
This is how your car moves.
车就是这样动的。
You have a spark and then everything starts running.
有了火花，一切就开始运转了。
Spark plugs are actually quite important, right?
火花塞其实挺重要的，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
So a spark is a very quick flash of light that comes out.
火花就是一瞬间闪出来的光。
That's right.
对。
It's not a long light.
不是持续的光。
It's just a spark.
只是一闪而过的火花。
So maybe when I strike a match or I use a lighter, there's a spark and that's what starts
所以，比如我划火柴或用打火机时，会有火花，那就是点燃
the fire.
火焰的东西。
That's right.
没错。
That's exactly right.
完全正确。
So a spark plug.
所以是火花塞。
And now we also check the oil levels of our car and that's a very important thing as well.
现在我们还会检查汽车的机油量，这也是很重要的事。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
So the oil level is something that you test with a long stick and you put it into the
机油量是用一根长棍来检测的，把它插进
engine, the oil container, and make sure that there is enough oil because if there's not
发动机的机油箱里，确保机油足够，因为如果机油
enough oil, you can have very serious car trouble.
不够，可能会引发严重的汽车故障。
That's right.
没错。
So a lot of technical or mechanical things that we're taking a look at.
所以我们看了很多技术或机械方面的东西。
Why don't we go back, let's review all these words and we'll be back in a bit.
我们不如回顾一下，复习所有这些词，一会儿再回来。
Welcome to Al's Garage.
欢迎来到阿尔的修车厂。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
No problem at all.
完全没问题。
I am taking a long road trip and I want to make sure my car is in good mechanical condition.
我要进行一次长途旅行，想确保车况良好。
Very wise decision.
非常明智的决定。
When was the last time you had a tune-up?
你上次做保养是什么时候？
Not that long ago.
没多久之前。
I think it was four months ago.
我想是四个月前。
We usually recommend that you bring your car in every 5,000 kilometers.
我们通常建议每5000公里把车送来检查一次。
Why?
为什么？
I mean, what exactly do you do to a car that you need to check it so often?
我是说，到底要对车做什么检查，需要这么频繁？
First of all, we change the motor oil and oil filter.
首先，我们会更换机油和机油滤清器。
If you don't do this, it can cause your engine to wear faster and that means you would probably
如果不这样做，会导致发动机磨损更快，那可能就得
have to change the pistons and intake valves.
更换活塞和进气阀了。
I see.
我明白了。
What else?
还有呢？
We also check your spark plugs, fuel filter, and other oil levels such as hydraulic fluid.
我们还会检查火花塞、燃油滤清器，以及其他油液，比如液压油。
We also check the clutch and brakes to determine when you will need new ones.
我们还会检查离合器和刹车，判断什么时候需要更换新的。
Okay.
好的。
Well, when you put it that way, it doesn't seem like a waste of time and money.
嗯，听你这么一说，这倒不像是浪费时间和钱了。
Trust me.
相信我。
Regular tune-ups will keep your car running smoothly and avoid breakdowns.
定期保养能让你的车运行顺畅，避免抛锚。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now we've prepared three key phrases for you.
现在我们为你准备了三个关键短语。
Let's take a look at those now on Fluency Builder.
让我们在流利度练习中看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度练习。
This first phrase is something that you often hear in the service industry.
第一个短语在服务行业经常听到。
So anytime you're going to a shop or maybe in this case, the mechanic, the mechanic will
所以，无论你去商店，还是像这里去修车厂，修车工会
say to you, what seems to be the problem?
对你说：“有什么问题吗？”
That's right.
没错。
So this is a question and we're saying, what is wrong with your car?
这是一个问句，意思是“你的车出了什么问题？”
Or maybe if you go to the doctor, the doctor will say, what seems to be the problem?
或者，如果你去看医生，医生也会说：“有什么问题吗？”
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
So this means what's wrong with you?
所以这意思是“你哪里不舒服？”
Where do you have a problem?
“你哪里有问题？”
This is a very, very common phrase.
这是一个非常非常常见的短语。
So remember this one.
记住这个。
It just means what's going on?
它只是表示“发生什么事了？”
Why are you here?
“你为什么来这里？”
What can I help you with?
“我能帮你什么？”
It's very polite though, right?
不过它很礼貌，对吧？
It's better than saying what's wrong with you.
比直接说“你怎么了”要好。
No, yeah.
不，是的。
You wouldn't want to say what's wrong with you.
你不会想说“你怎么了”。
That's very rude.
那很粗鲁。
So what seems to be the problem is a much more polite way of saying things.
所以“有什么问题吗”是一种更礼貌的表达方式。
Very good.
非常好。
And well, the mechanic, after explaining everything, he said that, you know, doing all these things,
而且，修车工在解释完所有事情后说，做这些事，
changing the filters will keep the car running smoothly.
更换滤清器能让车运行顺畅。
Okay.
好的。
So we're not talking about running like a marathon here.
我们这里说的不是像跑马拉松那样跑。
We're talking about using your car.
我们说的是使用汽车。
And so when we turn a car on, we don't say that the car is operating.
当我们启动汽车时，我们不说车在“运行”。
Really, we say it's running.
实际上，我们说它在“运转”。
So that means that it's in use, that I've turned the key and the motor is running.
所以意思是它在使用中，我转动钥匙，发动机在运转。
But if it's running well, we say it's running smoothly.
但如果它运转良好，我们就说它“运行顺畅”。
So it's not having any problems.
所以就是没有任何问题。
Yeah.
是的。
So if you turn your car on and you hear your engine, it sounds very normal, no problems.
所以如果你启动汽车，听到发动机声音很正常，没问题。
It's running smoothly.
它运行顺畅。
If it's going, it's not running smoothly.
如果它有问题，就不是运行顺畅了。
That's right.
没错。
And obviously, if you don't take care of your car, what may happen is you may suffer a breakdown.
显然，如果你不好好保养你的车，可能会发生故障。
Okay.
好的。
Remember this phrase as a phrase, because obviously things can break.
记住这个短语，因为显然东西会坏掉。
You know, I broke a glass.
你知道，我打碎了一个玻璃杯。
But as far as cars are concerned, you say, you know, a car breaks down or I want to avoid
但就汽车而言，你会说，车抛锚了，或者我想避免
breakdowns.
故障。
And so this is something that happens when your car no longer works properly.
所以这就是当你的车不再正常工作时发生的事情。
That's right.
没错。
So you say, my car broke down yesterday.
所以你会说，我的车昨天抛锚了。
And I had to call a friend to pick me up because you know, when your car breaks down, you can't
我不得不打电话给朋友来接我，因为你知道，当你的车抛锚时，你哪儿也
go anywhere.
去不了。
You can't drive it anymore.
你再也开不动它了。
Very good.
很好。
So to break down now, obviously, if you get a flat tire, that doesn't really mean that
那么说到抛锚，显然，如果你轮胎瘪了，那并不真正意味着
your car broke down.
你的车抛锚了。
No, a flat tire is a bit different.
不，轮胎瘪了有点不同。
That means that you have to replace the tire.
那意味着你得换轮胎。
But when your car breaks down, it means that something inside the car, like a piece of
但当你的车抛锚时，意味着车内部的东西，比如
it, yeah, the transmission or the spark plugs or the engine, some part of it isn't working
嗯，变速箱、火花塞或发动机，某个部件工作不正常，
right and you have to get it fixed or replaced.
你得修理或更换它。
That's right.
没错。
Okay, so a lot of interesting things talking about cars here.
好的，关于汽车我们聊了很多有趣的东西。
Why don't we take a look at our dialogue again.
我们不如再看一遍我们的对话。
Let's listen to it and be back in a bit.
让我们听一下，一会儿回来。
Welcome to Al's Garage.
欢迎来到阿尔的修车厂。
What seems to be the problem?
有什么问题吗？
No problem at all.
一点问题都没有。
I am taking a long road trip and I want to make sure my car is in good mechanical condition.
我要进行一次长途旅行，想确保我的车机械状况良好。
Very wise decision.
非常明智的决定。
When was the last time you had a tune-up?
你上次做调试是什么时候？
Not that long ago.
没多久之前。
I think it was four months ago.
我想是四个月前。
We usually recommend that you bring your car in every 5,000 kilometers.
我们通常建议你每5000公里把车开过来一次。
Why?
为什么？
I mean, what exactly do you do to a car that you need to check it so often?
我的意思是，你们到底对车做什么，需要这么频繁地检查？
First of all, we change the motor oil and oil filter.
首先，我们更换机油和机油滤清器。
If you don't do this, it can cause your engine to wear faster and that means you would probably
如果你不这样做，会导致发动机磨损更快，那意味着你可能
have to change the pistons and intake valves.
得更换活塞和进气阀。
I see.
我明白了。
What else?
还有什么？
We also check your spark plugs, fuel filter, and other oil levels such as hydraulic fluid.
我们还会检查你的火花塞、燃油滤清器和其他油液，比如液压油。
We also check the clutch and brakes to determine when you will need new ones.
我们还会检查离合器和刹车，以确定你何时需要更换新的。
Okay, well, when you put it that way, it doesn't seem like a waste of time and money.
好的，嗯，你这么一说，这看起来就不像是浪费时间和金钱了。
Trust me.
相信我。
Regular tune-ups will keep your car running smoothly and avoid breakdowns.
定期调试会让你的车运行顺畅，避免故障。
Okay, so talking about cars and tune-ups.
好的，那么说到汽车和调试。
Now, when we go to the mechanic, you saw that he said, welcome to Al's Garage.
现在，当我们去修车厂时，你看到他说的，欢迎来到阿尔的修车厂。
So a mechanic shop is usually called a garage.
所以修车店通常被称为修车厂。
That's right.
没错。
And as you will know, a garage is a place where we store cars.
而且你知道，车库是存放汽车的地方。
So sometimes people park their cars in the street.
所以有时人们把车停在街上。
But if you have a special place to protect your car from the rain or the snow, like a
但如果你有一个专门的地方保护你的车免受雨雪侵袭，比如一个
room for your car, that's called a garage.
车的房间，那就叫车库。
And this might be confusing, but a store, like you say, for a mechanic is a garage also
这可能有点让人困惑，但修车店，比如你说的修车厂，也叫车库，
because there's a door that opens up the same way.
因为门也是那样打开的。
It opens up, not out.
它是向上开的，不是向外开的。
And you pull the car inside and then the mechanic can fix the car.
你把车开进去，然后修车工可以修车。
And so I think that's why it's a garage.
所以我想这就是为什么它叫车库。
There's room for many cars inside.
里面可以停很多车。
That's right.
没错。
So you take, or if your car is at the mechanic shop, you would say, oh, my car is at the
所以如果你的车在修车店，你会说，哦，我的车在
garage.
修车厂。
It's getting fixed.
正在修理。
Yeah, that's right.
嗯，没错。
But it's a little bit different from the place where you would buy a car.
但这和买车的地方有点不同。
A place where you buy a car is a car lot, L-O-T, lot.
买车的地方是汽车销售场，L-O-T，lot。
And that's a place where they have many, many cars outside, like in a big parking lot.
那是一个外面有很多很多车的地方，就像一个大停车场。
That's what we call a lot.
我们称之为销售场。
And you can pick a car and buy it and test it.
你可以选车、买它并试驾。
But a place where you fix a car, not special, that's called a garage or a repair shop.
但修车的地方，不是特别的，那叫修车厂或修理店。
Now, something that's very interesting and very common in places like the States and
现在，一个非常有趣且在美国和加拿大等地很常见的事情是，
Canada is that there are actually used car lots where you can see many cars that are
实际上有二手车销售场，你可以看到很多
used and they're trying to sell.
二手车，他们正在试图出售。
But obviously in many other countries, it's not very common to see a used car lot.
但显然在许多其他国家，二手车销售场并不常见。
Well, I think in America, people like to buy new cars and that means that every couple
嗯，我想在美国，人们喜欢买新车，这意味着每隔
of years, they sell their old car.
几年，他们就会卖掉旧车。
But that car is still good.
但那辆车仍然很好。
You can still use a car from 2005.
你仍然可以使用2005年的车。
In fact, when I had a car, it was from 1991.
事实上，当我有车时，那是一辆1991年的车。
It was 16 years old at the time.
那辆车当时已经16年了。
And so I could still drive it.
所以我还能开它。
It was a good car.
它是一辆好车。
And I think that as long as you can drive it, you can sell it.
我觉得只要车还能开，你就能卖掉它。
This is actually another interesting thing about cars in general in places like this
这其实是关于像这样的地方汽车的一个有趣现象，
is that there are so many cars.
就是车太多了。
And as you say, people are often buying new cars every year or trading their cars every
就像你说的，人们经常每年买新车，或者每
five years, let's say.
五年换一次车。
Used cars are very, very, very inexpensive.
二手车非常非常便宜。
I mean, you can get a car for like $500 sometimes.
我的意思是，有时候你花500美元就能买到一辆车。
That's right.
没错。
And in a lot of cases, it doesn't make sense to buy a new car because it's going to be
在很多情况下，买新车并不划算，因为新车
less valuable in one day.
一天之内就会贬值。
But a used car, as long as it doesn't have any problems, like you don't want to buy a
但二手车，只要没什么问题，比如你不想买
car that has faulty spark plugs or whatever.
火花塞有毛病的车之类的。
But as long as it runs smoothly, I think that it's a very good investment to buy a used
但只要它运行顺畅，我觉得买一辆二手
car.
车是个很好的投资。
Very good.
非常好。
So it's interesting because in many countries, used cars are actually not that much cheaper.
有趣的是，在很多国家，二手车其实并没有便宜那么多。
So why don't you come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以，欢迎访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Let us know if taking your car to the mechanic is very expensive or buying a used car is
告诉我们，把你的车送去修理厂是不是很贵，或者买二手车
still relatively expensive.
是不是仍然相对昂贵。
We hope to see you guys there and until next time.
我们期待在那里见到你们，下次再见。
Bye.
再见。
Tip your car wastes to reuse an old car.
提示：把你的旧车废物利用，重新使用。